Dipin Sonwani

 $+91\ 8411953919 \cdot \underline{dipinsonwani@gmail.com} \cdot \underline{https://github.com/dipinsonwani} \cdot \underline{https://www.linkedin.com/in/dipin-sonwani-05502497}$

Mumbai, India

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I am an engineer with 4 years of product focused app development experience where I focus on solving problems for clients and end-users while working towards improving the performance, scalability and reliability of the app. Someone who enjoys turning apps into an experience for users, has worked on consumer facing high performance app from the scratch and led a team to maintain the app. Actively giving talks and attending in tech events in my free time, while also maintaining my personal fitness.

TECH STACK

Engineering Practises	TDD, Design Patterns, Pair programming, Oops, Git for Version Control, github workflow (Github Actions), Researching first and estimating later, Code reviews
Languages	Dart, Java, C, Python, Javascript, ZSH
Skills	Flutter SDK, Android, NodeJs, GCP, Firebase, Serverless Cloud Functions, expressjs

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer at Orange Power Ltd | London, UK

Dec 2022 - Present

Orange Power Ltd -

Achieved recognition as one of the top finalists for Tech Nation Rising Stars due to innovative work in energy flexibility, with a mission to enable end consumers to achieve net zero targets at minimal cost. The developed app also received a top ranking in the UK Google Play Store's House and Home category, achieving a highly impressive third place.

- Responsible for writing code with their test cases and rapidly delivering app feature designs.
- Responsible for contributing technical ideas and suggestions to enhance the direction of the product
- Led the development and maintenance of a cross-platform app, ensuring optimal performance and reliability by leveraging a single codebase for **Android, iOS and web** using Flutter SDK.
- Responsible for reviewing code and leaving feedback with maintaining solid engineering principles
- Implemented robust, scalable apps for mobile and web platforms by leveraging the Bloc pattern for state management
- · Responsible for maintaining deployment process (CI/CD) with GitHub workflows, Codemagic
- Maintaining the reliability of the overall system by exposing custom performance metrics and setting up observability and alerting on **Firebase crashlytics**.
- Created OpenAPI specification to generate serialisable models, ensuring consistency and reliability in data exchange between client and server.
- Proficient in implementing clean architecture principles for scalable and maintainable code using TDD.

Senior Flutter developer at Newlit technologies

Apr 2021 - Dec 2022

Newlit technologies -

One of the National award winner in StartUpIndia product consultancy, creating deeply focused and crafted digital experiences. It is co-pilot to Engineers and Design teams to provide visibility, observability, and make it feasible to ship software faster while creating convenient outcomes for our clients.

- Developed Full-stack mobile applications using latest industry-adopted technologies and frameworks.
- Worked on backend using **Node.js**, **expressjs** as well as Integrating **REST Apis**.
- Responsible for release management every alternate week cycle
- Responsible for analysing product specifications and design implementations in the design-engineer handoff.
- Re-factor major components of the system to make the overall system more performant
- Managed and coordinated a team in maintaining and updating app features, optimizing performance and reliability while responding to changing user needs.
- Developed apps using **Bloc** and **Provider** state management techniques.

EDUCATION

Bachelor Of Engineering in IT 2016 - 2020

Thadomal Shahani Engineering college, Bandra, Mumbai.

PERSONAL PROJECTS

E-commerce app

- Developed a feature-rich e-commerce app on Flutter SDK, implementing user authentication via REST APIs and SharedPreferences for caching user preferences.
- Utilized Clean Architecture and Provider state management library to ensure a well-structured, responsive, and scalable app.
- Link: <u>dipinsonwani/shop_app</u>

Personal expenses app

- Developed an app on Flutter SDK, in which transactions can be added, deleted, and can be viewed in a Custom graph widget.
- Link: <u>dipinsonwani/personal_expenses_app</u>